A Guide to the V.P.I. Alumni Association World War II Alumni Cards, c. 1939-1954
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
V.P.I. Alumni Association World War II Alumni Cards, c. 1939-1959
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
RG 29d
1.83 Cubic Feet; 12 boxes
These cards include information the Alumni Assosication kept on students from Virginia Tech who served in World War II. The cards list personal information about the soldiers organized by class year, from 1892 through 1949. The collection also includes liberated, wounded, and citation records.
Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Alumni Association; Virginia Polytechnic Institute
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The collection was transfered to Special Collections prior to 2017.
Scope and Content
The V.P.I. Alumni Association World War II Alumni Cards, RG 29d, includes cards with information on individuals from the V.P.I. Alumni Association World War II Record. The personal information listed on the cards includes the soldier's name, rank, class, branch and unit of service, date called to active duty, promotions (with dates), foreign service, and additional remarks found on the back of the card.
Arrangement
The V.P.I. Alumni Association World War II Alumni Cards are organized in alphabetical order by surname within the following series:
Series I: Liberated
Series II: Wounded
Series III: Citations
Series IV: Last known post of an idividual
Subseries A: APO-NY
Subseries B: FPO-NY
Subseries C: Korea-Japan, APO, S.F.
Subseries D: USA-APO, Seattle, Washington
Subseries E: USA
Series V: Class Year. This is organized chronologically by class year, then alphabetically by surname.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Virginia Polytechnic Institute. Alumni Association; University History; University Archives
Contents List
- Series I: Liberated, 1942-1945
  - Liberated, 1942-1945 (Box 1)
- Series II: Wounded, 1942-1945
  - Wounded, 1942-1945 (Box 1)
- Series III: Citations, 1942-1946
  - A-Ja, 1942-1946 (Box 1)
  - Je-Z, 1942-1946 (Box 2)
- Series IV: Last known post, 1943-1959
  - Subseries A: APO-NJ, 1949-1953
    - A-Garl, 1949-1953 (Box 2)
    - Garv-Z, 1949-1953 (Box 3)
  - Subseries B: FPO-NY, 1949-1952 (Box 3)
  - Subseries C: Korea-Japan, APO, S.F., 1948-1952 (Box 3)
  - Subseries D: USA-APO, Seattle, Washington, 1950-1954 (Box 3)
  - Subseries E: USA, 1943-1959 (Box 4)
- Series V: Class Year, 1892-1949
  - Class of 1892-Class of 1916 (Box 4)
  - Class of 1917-Class of 1933 (Box 5)
  - Class of 1934-Class of 1938 (Box 6)
  - Class of 1938-Class of 1940 (Box 7)
  - Class of 1940-Class of 1942 (Box 8)
  - Class of 1942-Class of 1944 (Box 9)
  - Class of 1944-Class of 1945 (Box 10)
  - Class of 1945-Class of 1946 (Box 11)
  - Class of 1946-Class of 1949 (Box 12)